# **Subhankar Rout**

**User Experience Designer | Product Designer** 



Watch My Video CV

- +91 9337663465
- subhankarrout.kiit@gmail.com
- > linkedin.com/in/subhankarrout
- www.subhankarrout.in/portfolio

# **Summary**

As a User Experience Designer, I merge creativity with technical expertise to craft engaging designs, leading numerous projects that boost user satisfaction by an average of 30%. My collaborative efforts with 100+ professionals yield innovative designs that resonate deeply with users, reflecting a commitment to excellence in user experience.

# **Experience**

#### Senior User Experience Designer

Deligence Technologies Inc. | Jan 2024 - Present

- As a Senior User Experience Designer, I revamped a leading educational game's interface and interaction design, increasing user engagement by 20%, and reduced user drop-off rates by 15%.
- My tasks include designing wireframes, prototypes, user research and user flows to enhance the overall user experience.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to integrate user feedback into design iterations, resulting in a user satisfaction score increase of 30%.

#### Visual Interaction Designer

RPATech, Gurugram | Oct 2020 - January 2024

- As a Visual Interaction Designer, I developed engaging visual content for top-rated online courses, resulting in a 40% increase in course enrollment on platforms like Coursera and Udemy.
- Crafted user interfaces and experiences for our Robotic Process Automation (RPA) projects.
- Enhanced learning experiences through collaborative stakeholder engagement and effective design solutions.

### **Certifications**

# **Project Management Professional Certification**

Atlassian, Aha! and IIBA | 2024

 Develop a deep understanding of Product life cycle management, roadmaps and Agile Project Management

### **UX Design Professional Certification**

Google LLP | 2023

• Learned to conduct research, white boarding, and prototype creation in UX Design.

## **User Experience Designer Certification Course**

LinkedIn Learning | 2021

• Gained skills in using UI/UX tools for designing and prototyping user interfaces.

# Brand Management: Aligning Business, Brand and Behavior

London Business School | 2021

Learned to align brand strategy with product development.

# How to ChatGPT: Master the Art of Prompt Engineering

Udemy Learning | 2023

Learned prompt engineering and how to effectively use ChatGPT.

# **Education**

#### **GIET University, Gunupur**

Bachelor of Technology in Electrical Engineering | 2017 - 2021

## **Skills**

#### Design

 $\label{thm:continuous} User\ Experience \cdot Interaction\ Design \cdot User\ Interface \cdot Prototyping \cdot Visual\ Design \cdot Wireframing \cdot Mockups\ Design$ 

#### Research

User Interview · User Testing · Heuristic Evaluation · Design System · Information Architecture · Journey Mapping · Quantitative Analysis · A/B Testing · Competitor Analysis · Brand Strategy

#### Software

Figma · Miro · Photoshop · Premiere Pro · After Effects · Adobe XD · Camtasia · Jira · Qualtrics · Survey Monkey · Illustrator · HTML · CSS · Js (basic)

#### Visual Design

Poster Design  $\cdot$  Branding  $\cdot$  Typography  $\cdot$  Iconography  $\cdot$  Book Design  $\cdot$  Mobile Application Design (iOS and Android)  $\cdot$  Webapp Design, Stylesheets and Guidelines

#### Methodologies

 $Scrum \cdot Agile \cdot Waterfall \ (PM) \cdot Design \ Thinking \ (Product \ Design)$ 

#### Other Skills

 $\label{eq:collaboration} \textbf{Collaboration and Communication} \cdot \textbf{Problem Solving} \cdot \textbf{Team} \\ \textbf{Management} \cdot \textbf{Project Management} \cdot \textbf{Stakeholder Management} \\$ 

# **Achievements**

UI Design Excellence - Deligence Technologies Inc. | 2024
Appreciation for fast learning and Implementations - DT | 2024
Annual Excellence Award by CEO - RPATech | 2022
Creativity and Innovation Recognition by AVP - RPATech | 2021
Innovation Challenge Runners-up - IEEE GIETU | 2020
Filmmaker Champion - NSS MBD Camp | 2019
Best Filmmaker Award - GIET University | 2018

# **Extra-curricular Activities**

- Authored a published English novel, showcasing creativity and storytelling skills.
- Recognized by the Commissioner of Municipality, Rourkela, for contributions to literature and culture.
- Featured in news outlets for both novel and music albums.
- Created and managed the "S4 Cinesphere" YouTube channel, producing music albums and short films during college.

# Language

#### **English and Hindi**

(Proficient in understanding, writing, and speaking)